theprairiehomestead.com 2019-05-10

# Privacy Policy • The Prairie Homestead

Your privacy is of the utmost importance to us here at The Prairie Homestead.

The Prairie Homestead (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website. This Website may contain third-party links to other websites which are not governed by this policy.

**_What Information Do We Collect and How Is This Information Used?_**

  1. We may receive and store information that you voluntarily submit through the Website for the purpose of subscribing to the Website to receive newsletters, for the purpose of leaving comments on blog posts, or administering sweepstakes, contests or promotions. Examples of information collected for this purpose are your name, email address and website URL. This information is only captured when you voluntarily enter or opt-in and enter this information for collection.
  2. We may receive and store certain types of usage-related information when you interact with the Website, including but not limited to, your computer’s IP address and browser information. The information we collect is used to customize the content and/or layout of our page for each individual visitor.
  3. We use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. No personal information is shared with the Website’s ad providers.
  4. The Website uses Google Analytics to track statistics regarding our audience and Website traffic. No personally identifiable information is transferred from the Website to Google Analytics. [For more information on Google’s Analytics privacy policies, please visit this site](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).
  5. This Website engages in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.
  6. The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described above.
  7. The Prairie Homestead is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

**_Third-Party Use of Personal Information_**

The Website may provide personal information to an applicable third party in order to provide services. Currently, the Website uses the services of ConvertKit for delivery of email updates and newsletters. ConvertKits use of your personal information is subject to ConvertKit’s privacy policy.

Your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications.

Information that does not identify you personally may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**_Will We Share the Personal Information It Collects?_**

We will not sell, distribute, or reveal users’ email addresses or other personal information without their consent. This does not include third-party partners, such as those listed above.

**_Modification or Deletion of Personal Information_**

You can decline to submit personal information at any time. If you decline, we may not be able to continue to provide service to you. You may request deletion of your personal information by sending an email to info(at)theprairiehomestead(dot)com, but in some cases, we may be required to keep your information by law. In such a case, it would no longer be active and would be kept separately in an archive.

We also often link to other websites or blogs. However, these websites are out of our control and we do not necessarily endorse all the content on these websites. So please surf responsibly.
